LAM PHAM

phone 408-668-4014

email lamqpham101@gmail.com

website lampham.co

User Experience Designer motivated by user satisfaction.

The opportunity to create and rethink interfaces to make software pleasing for everyone to use is what drives me to design. The experiences I gained have taught me a lot about user behavior and how I can design for not only the business but also the users.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego - Cognitive Science - Human Computer Interaction, Expected 2019

COURSEWORK

- Java Object Oriented Programming
- Interaction Design

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Discrete Math for Computer Science

PROJECTS

TOTAL BODY DEVELOPMENT

January 2017 - Present

- Conducted user research, competitive analysis, storyboarding, wire framing, prototyping, and built the resulting web app with HTML, CSS, and AJAX.
- Handled need finding, user testing sessions, as well as A/B testing with Google Analytics to utilize the UX methodology to increase the usability of the resulting product, a workout app tailored to beginners.

TRITON BITES December 2015 - Present

- Developed and designed an intuitive mobile Android app to fetch menu data for UCSD dining halls.
- Applied knowledge of Java programming and HTML to apply the JSOUP library to scrape UCSD dining hall menus and list them in a more readable manner.
- Gained knowledge in Android development and testing as well as UX design and data structures.

EXPERIENCE

USER EXPERIENCE INTERN, CUBIC CORPORATION; SAN DIEGO, CA

May 2017 - Present

- Streamlined business process in SAP to drastically improve efficiency and reduce chances of error by working with users to remove unnecessary steps and reorganize interface elements.
- Designed and developed user interfaces and flows for said processes for ease of use, legibility, and visual attractiveness as well as create a Cubic style guide for future designers.
- Presented final redesigned business processes to users, managers, and executives.

INSTRUCTOR, CODING4YOUTH; CUPERTINO, CA

June 2016 - May 2017

- Instructed students of all grade levels from elementary to high school the basics of coding.
- Utilized the Greenfoot Java IDE to educate students of beginner skill level the essentials of object oriented programming in Java.
- Taught higher level students the more advanced topics of Java such as recursion and data structures.

TECH MENTOR, SEVEN TREES LIBRARY; SAN JOSE, CA

February 2013 - July 2014

- One on one instruction to visitors in a variety of technological applications including but limited to, Microsoft Office, email skills, mobile device troubleshooting, and internet skills.
- Assisted others with computer programming help such as Java and C as well as device troubleshooting and optimization such as switching out RAM and laptop tune ups.
- Promoted to instruct a class of around 20 students to learn the basics of computing.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Java, Javascript, C, C++, HTML/CSS, XML, Bash

TOOLS: Android SDK/Studio, Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, Vim, Unix, Google Analytics

COMMUNICATION: English, Vietnamese, Spanish (limited working proficiency)